# JIAWEI DU

■ isjiawei.du@gmail.com 🛅 <u>LinkedIn</u> 😝 <u>Github</u> 🖝 Google Scholar 🗥 Webpage

#### Research Profile

Jiawei's research is centered on speech technology and its applications, including Neural Audio Codec, Generative AI, Automatic Speaker Verification (ASV), and Audio Deepfake Detection & Localization. These research directions aim to assist in distinguishing truth from falsehood and generating more authentic content in the era of AIGC proliferation.

#### Education

#### National Taiwan University

2022 - Present

M.S. in Computer Science and Information Engineering (CSIE), GPA 4.13/4.3

Taipei, Taiwan

- $\bullet$  Ranking 1/201 in the department in the 2023/24 academic year.
- Supervised by Prof. Jyh-Shing Roger Jang in NTU MIRLab.

#### Ming Chuan University

2018 - 2022

B.S. in Information and Telecommunications Engineering (ITE), GPA 3.98/4.0

Taoyuan, Taiwan

- Ranking 1/79 in the department cumulatively.
- Under the mentorship of Prof. Shu-Yin Chiang in the area of Robotics.

#### Shanghai Jiao Tong University

2020 - 2021

Exchange Student in Computer Science and Technology

Shanghai, Chinese mainland

• Core Courses: Digital Signal Processing, Digital Graphics Processing, Computer Network, Computer Vision

#### **Publications**

# Empower Typed Descriptions by Large Language Models for Speech Emotion

2024

Accepted, APSIPA ASC 2024

Haibin Wu, Huang-Cheng Chou, Kai-Wei Chang, Lucas Goncalves, **Jiawei Du**, Jyh-Shing Roger Jang, Chi-Chun Lee, Hung-yi Lee

# DFADD: The Diffusion and Flow-Matching Based Audio Deepfake Dataset

2024

Accepted, SLT 2024

**Jiawei Du\***, I-Ming Lin\*, I-Hsiang Chiu\*, Xuanjun Chen, Haibin Wu, WenZe Ren, Yu Tsao, Hung-yi Lee, Jyh-Shing Roger Jang

# Open-Emotion: A Reproducible EMO-SUPERB for Speech Emotion Recognition Systems

2024

Accepted, SLT 2024

Haibin Wu, Huang-Cheng Chou, Kai-Wei Chang, Lucas Goncalves, **Jiawei Du**, Jyh-Shing Roger Jang, Chi-Chun Lee, Hung-yi Lee

#### Codec-SUPERB @ SLT 2024: A lightweight benchmark for neural codec models

2024

Accepted, SLT 2024

Haibin Wu, Xuanjun Chen, Yi-Cheng Lin, **Jiawei Du**, Kai-Wei Chang, Ke-Han Lu, Alexander Liu, Ho Lam Chung, Yuan-Kuei Wu, Dongchao Yang, Songxiang Liu, Yi-Chiao Wu, Xu Tan, James Glass, Shinji Watanabe, Hung-yi Lee

#### Neural Codec-based Adversarial Sample Detection for Speaker Verification

2024

Accepted, Interspeech 2024

Xuanjun Chen\*, Jiawei Du\*, Haibin Wu, Jyh-Shing Roger Jang, Hung-Yi Lee

#### EMO-SUPERB: An In-depth Look at Speech Emotion Recognition

2024

Prevrint

Haibin Wu, Huang-Cheng Chou, Kai-Wei Chang, Lucas Goncalves, **Jiawei Du**, Jyh-Shing Roger Jang, Chi-Chun Lee, Hung-Yi Lee

#### Dcase 2023 task 6b: Text-to-audio retrieval using pretrained models

2023

Accepted, DCASE2023 Challenge, Tech. Rep, 2023

Chung-Che Wang\*, Jiawei Du\*, Jyh-Shing Roger Jang

# Research Experiences

Deepfake Detection 06/2022 - Present

- Audio-Visual: Explored the limitations of current state-of-the-art (SOTA) Audio-Visual Deepfake Detection methods, and improved the mAP@50 from 13.1% to 75.7% on our private AV Deepfake dataset.
- Singing Deepfake: Achieved outstanding on the CtrSVDD dataset, reducing the previous SOTA Equal Error Rate (EER) by 50%.
- ASVspoof: Researched and applied nearly all methods from the past five years, including RawNet2, AASIST, Wav2Vec2-AASIST, etc.

#### Audio-Text Cross-Modal Learning

02/2022 - 06/2022

 Investigated language-based audio-text retrieval. Redesigned and explored the performance of different models in speech-text retrieval, and experimented with various data augmentation methods.

## Academic Cctivity

- Reviewer of 2024 International Journal of Pattern Recognition and Artificial Intelligence (IJPRAI 2024).
- Reviewer of 2024 IEEE Spoken Language Technology Workshop (SLT 2024).
- Technical committee of Codec-SUPERB Challenge at SLT 2024.

# **Projects**

Pick and Place Perler Beads by a Six-axis Robotic Arm using Image Recognition 01/2021 - 12/2022Information and Telecommunications Engineering, Ming Chuan University Final Year Project

- Imaging processing by de-shadowing to achieve highly accurate recognition of beads' locations by Hough circle transform (HCT).
- Responsible for the algorithm and device design of the robotic arm.
- Created C# WinForms and programming to visualize and control the robotic arm.

Research on Algorithms of Medical Image Enhancement Based on Noise OCT Computer Science and Technology, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

10/2020 - 01/2021

Term Project

- Compared the capacity of denoising OCT images by Python among different algorithms (Side Window Filtering; Non-local Means; BM3D; Learning Self-Supervised Denoising from single image).
- The quality of images was enhanced by iterative denoising processes, and the enhancement of each algorithm was evaluated by the PSNR (Peak signal-to-noise ratio).

#### Honours and Awards

- SLT 2024 Travel Grant (10 were accepted, 42 submissions).
- Currently ranked 13/49 in the CtrlSVDD competition (total 74 participants, 130 submissions).
- DCASE Challenge 2023 Task 6b, ranked 3/10.
- Received one class ranking first scholarship and five departmental ranking first scholarships at Ming Chuan University.
- Masterpiece Award for General Course (ranked 4th) in Ming Chuan University
- Excellent Student Cadre by Association of Hubei Students in Taiwan

#### Extra-curricular Activities

#### Mainland – Taiwan Student Association

09/2019 - 04/2020

Ming Chuan University

Secretariat of general affairs

- In charge of overall budget planning and execution, purchasing, fundraising, communication with university administration and students.
- Planning and implementation of year-round, campus-wise activities.

# Skills

**Programming:** Python, PyTorch, C++

Typesetting: LaTeX, Markdown

Languages: Mandarin (native speaker), English (IELTS 6.5)

Hobbies: Singing, Piano, Guitar, Electronic Keyboard, City Walk, Traveling, NBA

Last Updated in Oct. 2024